well I clicked on the wrong one hello
live it's 8:30 in the morning this tie
works much better for me we'll see if
I'm still able to do it in a week I had
notes plans we were going to talk about
how were you going we were going to talk
about efficiency if redundancy I posted
I think Bonita Roy posted and then
someone posted to game B and I couldn't
really find it but it got a lot of my
wheels turning about efficiency and
redundancy and something Jaime Jaime I
think it was Jimmy wheel said in one of
the podcasts where he talked about why
he doesn't like utopians is that
utopians are always about maximizing for
one value for one part and so if you
maximize for efficiency it's gonna cost
you everything else and that's kind of
what we're seeing with the chrome virus
so that might be tomorrow's post widgets
today I just can't I just can't know
where all this gone it's got a little
crazy and I've been having this exchange
with somebody in the game B space this
morning and so that's where my mind is
that so I'm going to I won't share his
his name but I am gonna share it I'm
gonna read the thread because I don't
know it's where I am in the moment and
that's what I'm doing and maybe I'm in
the wrong maybe there is something for
me to learn here maybe when I reread it
so is it be like yes you are highly
offensive you should probably keep
yourself in check but anyway I this guy
had posted something I never saw
yesterday when he posted it but there's
a ton of people posting the game be
space so I post things that are I think
should be powerful and meaningful and
then there's crickets and I understand
that it's the algorithm and then posts
that probably shouldn't get any merit
get voted up just by people's commenting
on them and/or liking them so he posted
this morning stating he reposted the one
he posted from yesterday which is
already a little bit a little bit weird
let me just find annoying projects okay
he came right back up I'll read his last
response and the same in the same moment
because you'll get it too so he posted
saying art repost show me you care about
solutions
this is his post in a game be space
which gain blue space is full
of people who are there to try to
co-create solutions are there to see -
can we come up with a solution to the
world some people bring their own
solution or their pet project with them
and we all bring our baggage and we're
all individuals and humans of course but
is isn't very long so I'll just read it
and I honestly don't understand half of
what he say which is why I asked the one
question I asked ethanol nationalism
versus high trust opt in high trust is
preferred but not at the expense of the
advantages of homogeneity I feel like I
would know that word when it's not that
word natural law hierarchy is there
anyone arguing that we should still
transcend it completely before having
integrated it into our fundamental
social structure anyone have a better
rule than universally solving for
reciprocity game B is going to be old by
the time the solutions you all want are
applicable you're missing the window for
change because of the lack of
operational thought we have the answer
we have the answers we need we have the
moral leverage we need what are you all
waiting for what is there left to
discuss like we want to discuss my thing
and only my thing my thing is the thing
that makes sense and I'm like I don't
even know what you mean by universal
solving for reciprocity even though you
think that's the thing we should all
agree on I'm just gonna check in at
street yard opposite thoughts just you
watching hey um so I just responded with
I'm the only one who responded what does
universally solving for reciprocity look
like to you cuz I had no idea what he's
talking about he said what does it look
like to you I'm not the one who used
that word I don't even know what or that
sentence I said already said I mean no
lies full accounting and all
transactions which if you've watched me
for any amount of time know that I'm all
about transparency and it is a big value
that I hold I think it solves a lot of
problems having full accounting of those
things I just don't like reciprocity
because that word brings up to me tit
for tat that you have to give to get you
have to get to give and I think that's a
lot of the issues but that's my stuff
that's doesn't mean that everything that
is going to be created in the world has
to be under that umbrella it just means
that's what it is so I responded I'm not
sure what what you mean by it actually I
have no idea what that would look like
I do not envision
world where I need to account for
reciprocity I just want to do my part
give my bit and have a beautiful world
which is all I said senses and the Gabey
space this is like in the adder in the
end command cap group I'm part of I but
if expect in this exchange but not in
game be he said reciprocity means no
line in public spaces your answer no
offense
is that of a child here a this but
because otherwise would be just a normal
exchange you can have what you want you
have to accept the constraints and
duties that come with it imagine wanting
sovereignty but not wanting to at least
fairly trade for it and I have no way
I'm saying I don't want to fairly trade
I want to give my purpose and I don't
want to attach to my reciprocity
personally it's just my personal choice
it doesn't mean that that's how the
world should necessarily run so I'm just
trying to get into what he thinks we
should be doing so are you asking me to
paint you a picture imagine a world
where people can't lie when it counted I
love that world where our politicians in
our media account lying we have the
truth we can get more easily to
solutions I'm all for that
like this is a part I'd like actually
kind of agreed with you but like his
anyway it gets it gets so much better so
I I probably shouldn't have said the
next part but all I could do is picture
my seven-year-old constantly who's her
and her little friend are always like no
offense but you don't know how to do
ballet no offense you didn't do that
well we have to the other ones mom have
to constantly say it's funny if someone
just loved the comment that I could I'm
about to read a little my little kid in
the backseat with her friend be like no
offense that or she says it to me like
no offense figure that driver no offense
you don't know this no offense but and
it's like no offense doesn't mean no
offense in fact it means the opposite if
you have to put that in there and so I
was just picturing my seven girls he
called me and so is ironic could he use
no offense to anyway just say that I was
acting like a child I don't really care
if I'm acting like a child
your answer no offense is that of a
child I have in quotation mark mark
oh sorry index and quotation marks has
me laughing because I constantly have to
explain to my child that including no
offense does not actually mean no
offense it usually means the opposite
I have child Wonder and wizard wisdom
what are you doing to create the world
you want to live in he responded this is
the best ever I can you can just ignore
this money went on but that I didn't
bend or later no it meant they did I
know you're going to respond to me as if
I've insulted you no matter how I
present the notion that you are
generally lower agency than say a full
grown man when presented with the level
of responsibility that a full grown man
should be prepared to assume most or not
or even capable it's predictable that
you would want to somehow avoid taking
it so you've not understood what
reciprocity is which i think is my fault
so far maybe and you've made my post
into a value judgment on whether or not
my character is of high enough esteem to
be allowed to hold you and others to
account I can assure you I don't need
your permission you can fall in or be
left out this post is about trying to
include people like yourself so I'm
doing that at least is that what the
post is about because it didn't seem
like an invitation did not seem anyway
so I responded I ignored what he said
about full-grown agency of men because I
was like we're not gonna develop into
that misogyny but I responded what are
you doing to create the world you want
to live in how are you bringing
reciprocity to the world and he posted
this website on proper terian ism so I
so good he ever commented yet again I
responded is this your project and he
said I wouldn't call it a project thing
it's not mine fair enough I'd like to
talk people who's the owner of the
project so they can answer questions I
don't want to follow someone else's I
want to create something together but
yeah I think I asked her to go as this
project he said I wouldn't call it a
project and it's not mine
so I asked what are you doing and he
said is being patient with you I'm being
patient with you does that count I said
I don't know does it count to you I mean
as a full-grown man with more agency I
was expecting more smiling laughing face
how about behavior with some integrity
instead of undermining my good
intentions there's something for you to
learn here I can't say I've done a good
job lowering your defenses my defenses
are extremely low and
because I expect everyone to have agency
and practice you know make a rule but
anyway so I take this right before going
live
what would integrity look like to you in
this situation I have said nothing to
attack you and you have however insulted
me and everyone who is not a full-grown
man and compared me to a child and
insinuated I have a lack of integrity
maturity and agency
I suggest rereading this thread and
seeing what you can learn from it I have
to go do actual things in the world have
a great day Oh
Lodi okay he laughed at that which is
fine that's total lol women have lower
agency than men in general accepting
that is your first step to intellectual
integrity says the man doing nothing
will I'm doing like 230 things at once
that that's cool it's cool
to answer your question reading the
material I have shared before engaging
with me would demonstrate integrity
sorry once they see the other guy who I
know I actually don't actually own that
woman you know egos anyway we have a
it's all the anger tell me on the right
we have an another feminist as you guys
think I'm angry
oh good it's got into it so that any way
so that sidetracked my oh and then he
reported he reported it so that's I'll
have to know go do Indian in thing I'm
dealing with the thing that I was
commenting on because I am an admitted
or not in a been the immense the higher
running my mind moderators higher but
I'm a moderate or not admit anyway so
that was my morning which was actually
really fun I was like I don't know what
the same office who says that like but
don't worry in your evolution will just
be all in the kitchen making sandwiches
that's our role right like you know
nothing about me Oh where's a man to
save me I'm so glad that honestly the
game be space is so not like that that
even though I have experienced and
anybody's won his experience sexist I'm
just like anyone who said the other race
of the mind it's experiment to go with
everyone has experienced racism but more
so if you know
but as a woman like when people dismiss
what you say to zero a woman I guarantee
you that happens in every space because
of the subconscious bias that you you
don't look at someone be like you're a
woman I'm not gonna listen to you but
when a woman speaks you might be less
likely to hear okay you know it happens
all of the time you'll begin a meeting
and you'll say something and then a man
will say it and people will listen to
him and not to you it happens less often
to me I think because I have slightly
more of male like first I don't know I
don't know what happens less to me but
it still absolutely happens but like
where do you just full-on lays it out
like you're not a man you can't have
ages what does that even mean do I have
to be able to move a tree because I'm
actually fully in alignment that people
with testosterone coursing through their
body have more physical strength as
somebody with fibromyalgia and various
neurological problems honestly my kid
has more agency than I do if that's how
you're defining agency I can't pick
things up I can't I can't pick her up on
a regular basis that in no way means
that I we can don't have agency like my
physical body he's actually weak like my
physical body not because I'm female or
because of my health conditions and it
has made me so much stronger than your
average bear because it's like I have to
deal with the world looking at me like
like I'm weak and so when I know that's
not the case but anyway that was that
was today's today's fun fun adventure oh
I wonder how long he's been in the game
bees face he's not gonna last long he's
probably not gonna last beyond the day
because that that I think gets into the
kicked out permanently right away
category after this
oh my and I have I can't I can't even
deal with it out for this one of the
other moderators is gonna have to deal
with it because I have a conversation
with Jordan happen here in in half an
hour
Jordan calls one of the people who first
one of people instrumental in creating
gabey's only people who brought me into
game be like I liked his personality him
and Daniel Rockton Berger and Brett
Weinstein I really liked all three of
them and what they had to say but Daniel
and Brett I share a background with I'm
also a biologist and so when they speak
like it's it's very similar I there's
nothing I disagree with them on
their biological friends because of that
like I get it yes I'm biology and and
Jordan I don't know what his background
actually is I think like pewters and
such and he's um we had a conversation
right after I got into the game bSpace
talking about the technology cooperative
and I haven't talked to him since then
he left the game be Facebook group
anyway so I wanted and you didn't like a
Facebook post on his personal page
talking about the like we need to be
taking action right now because of
what's going on in the world and and so
I'm really interested in having that
conversation with him on what I've been
doing in the game be space since our
conversation in in beginning of October
late September which was again right
after I entered the space like I feel
like I've burned up students in the last
six seven months in the most awesome way
like I've really appreciated being in
that space because and it wasn't by
anyone requiring that I grow up like it
wasn't by anyone saying look you need to
meet this far to be part of it it was me
wanting to meet that bar wanting to show
up in a way like wanting to be part of a
conversation really enjoying that I met
other people who want to have the same
conversations that I want to have it was
autistic people have not all of them but
a lot of them have what's called a
special and trust and my special
interest is game be without ever having
known the lingo until I got there and so
funny to a community of people who want
to talk about your special interest
non-stop is about the greatest gift you
can give an autistic person and that's
what I found in in KP and so but then I
got there and I was like I know how to
save that one all they know how to
create game B which I know is
off-putting but at the same time like I
don't know how to how dit how to
communicate that another way other than
the truth which is that I know how to be
good very campy and an experienced tons
of other people who also feel the same
way right but they know how to they know
how to create can be and part of the
issue is that of course I understand
that nobody does and that's where my
idea actually is the fact that nobody
does
and let me create it together from the
ground up that we come to is because
every other lofty idea even this one I
this guy's like read every you want me
to read an entire website
I'm not taking reading assignments
that's like that's your if that's your
battle bar for integrity I'm not gonna
need it because I don't read repeat
assignment tonight I only read stuff
that my brain really wants to read
because the only way I don't fall asleep
during it right away
and unless you've experienced that part
of your nervous system you're not gonna
understand why it's like how hard is it
to read something but like even if you
don't have that part of your nervous
system there's clearly only so many
hours in a day and so much energy
somebody has to be able to read anything
watch anything might only be oh now
there's to be so maybe I won't get into
the next thing though now that I've
shared that because if I didn't share
that didn't read that that I would just
in the back of my mind I would have just
been laughing the whole time which I do
anyway because I always have background
stuff going on but there was just
another level
I'm like I love though how I even laid
it out I kind of ignored the agency part
he was like no no no the same agency is
really interesting interesting I can't
really moderate it at the moment because
one I'm in it so maybe I shouldn't be
the one moderating it but also I have
this and then I might go off in ten
minutes so maybe this one would be half
an hour today so that I can meditate for
before talking to Jordan but like I'm in
such a weird space because I I discount
a lot of what I do I just can't like I'm
like I'm not doing enough I need to be
doing more or I need to be doing more
well also owning that like with my
disability and just with my personality
my more can't look like other people's
like it's it's I have to find the what
is the word the diminishing rate of
return on everything in my life on
parenting on cooking on cleaning my
house where leg that is the only mature
guy like I'm never gonna have a hundred
percent clean house so what's gonna have
the biggest impact at least and I'm
never gonna be a pain trasparent who
takes my kids all the activities guess
what me if there is anybody right now
but what can what can I give the most
impact for for the time that I do have
for the energy I can devote to that and
it is meant and needing to be very
creative maybe you two figure that our
foods are the hardest one because you
actually it's diminishing rate of return
there's so much that we get from food
that it's a lot harder to do the
diminishing ready to return for
parenting to me it's like to make a
happy kid like it's like but have her be
a lifelong learner that she knows she is
valued and loved for exactly who she is
and that she's empowered to be who she
is in the world and I can maximize for
that no problem in by you Nora what
society says I have enough enough
capacity for that this may be the only
thing a German parent enos help raise
the resilience happy person who knows
that they matter
one two yet it's like I'm hoping it hmm
I usually have green tea but this one
joy and so but with food because you're
eating calories because you're getting
nutrients out of it because I only have
a certain amount of energy and done I I
can maximize for or I can do the freedom
diminishing rate of return on one of
those things but not all of them so I
can get 20 or 80 percent of my calories
from 20 percent of the food right yeah
80% of my nutrients to 24 from 20% of my
cost but I can't do all of that at once
I can't do everything not without a lot
of people also working together to do it
I know we can do it together but anyway
I was like one of any of that you know
oh that I'm so i discount what I'm doing
in this space and yet when I look at
what other people are doing in this
space granted they also have hope they
have full-time jobs I don't and they
have families and life as well but when
I look at what people are physically
doing in the space and like I'm actually
part of the naive the 20% doing the 80%
but I'm doing it in a diminishing rate
of returns way I'm doing it within my
capacity because I can't do it outside
of my capacity so what I'm doing is
holding ITA cafes on Tuesday I'm
participating and Eric's thing for a
mega group on Wednesdays which is not I
wouldn't consider that as part of my
contribution but it's definitely
something that I get
contributed but everyone who
participates in that gets something out
of it or they wouldn't keep showing up
every week and I both and giving and
getting that's part of and that's where
reciprocity although the word and when I
looked up the definition I was like
actually okay I'm gonna throw some
prosody it's actually about everyone
getting benefit and if we're talking
about that way I agree with it but when
libertarians come hit me there's this
like like this everyone needs to be
independent and you need to think like
me the biggest irony I can't and I felt
it like I get it I'm also I have an idea
that can save the world I want people to
come on board for my idea partly because
my idea isn't my idea it's something
that we create together it is about
right if I create this and then present
it to you I have to sell it to you if we
create together it's a completely
different energy and so that is what I
need to tap into I'm not looking at it's
it's happening - I'm gonna be the
Emperor of the world and I'm gonna be
the one who gets to create everything
for everyone
I want to tap into like our collective
intelligence because with collective
intelligence also comes collective
energy to actually put it out each of
the world and as somebody with limited
energy and an abundance of ideas that is
a problem because I can't have the
energy but any of it on the world by
myself and none of them are supposed to
be put out in the world by themselves
like a lot of what is happening like my
passion is bringing people together for
a conversation and using technology to
empower the masses to live the life you
want to live but I'm also a very risk
and first person so the idea of putting
any of my money or any of my energy into
actually creating the technology when I
don't know if people want it or lose it
is actually what I bring to the table
because other people who can code and
don't need to put money in are coding
all of these things but nobody's using
them because there's another thing I
encountered this morning which a baby ll
so share because it's coming up it also
kind of maybe um I don't know Stephen
called what was it called something
notes it was one of the like idea notes
maybe let's see I just thought I would
write a comment I go yeah right that's
already you know hello YouTube the chip
hello my
but this this note-taking idea it's just
it's a it looks like a branch
application where it's just someone puts
an idea on other people other people on
the team can say whether they like the
idea you can upload it I would totally
use it if it was free but it's not free
in fact they're pricey it's not on their
website I had to ask for it and they
send it me to it they want my email I'm
like nope not giving in my email then
it's like they're starting packages two
hundred and fifty dollars a month okay
for note-taking like oh is pay two
hundred you know this month for this
your economics might be broke let maybe
I'm wrong maybe they're breaking
millions I don't know then they say on
their pricing page that they have a free
option for not-for-profits people just
starting out people are going through
the accelerator which is awesome so I
was looking into that and I was like I
just want to see and I just want to try
it and see if it would work before even
signing up for the free option they want
you to have a live demo with them and so
I was so I was like fine I'll have a
live demo I'm good with that
but all of their times because they're
in Europe are either astronomically late
when my brain is off or astronomically
early when I'm sleeping so my brain can
work through the day so the times did
work so I just want to play around with
the tool I don't think it's not that
complex of a tool I don't know why he
would need a demo besides the fact you
want to sell me a $250 luck package it's
like but what I want to do one of the
ideas that's been coming through for the
last few days that's what I have been
doing a solution raising which is
getting together for an hour-long
conversation and at the end we have
potential solutions that we could
actually create together if we had ten
thousand people in a hundred thousand
dollars they're not things we're going
to create and make the rest of the world
use it's like can we create a solution
for ten thousand people
what would ten thousand people creating
a a food app look like right like what
so it meets their needs not so that the
app gets provided for and all of the
apps that are out there solving the
problem they're solving and they're
awesome are charging way too much money
for it and so I'm both coming at it from
both ends that like well I'm gonna work
through solutions you can figure out now
that we have these six different
gentle solutions how do we work through
creating a process to get 10,000 people
and how do we work through creating a
process to have ever more people so you
only had the conversation with three to
five people
yeah they don't it's not competitive
right Steven anyway and so like you have
a dozen different team working apps out
there right Monday calm and idea notes
and all these different things none of
them are perfect none of them have all
of the features and all of them cost
money and they all cost much like
ridiculous amounts of money where it's
like per team player your team person
well if you have your only start up with
your own capital and you're getting
millions of dollars no problem spend
tens of thousands of dollars on other
people's apps so that you can but like
it's not integrating together so doesn't
work well they're not gonna be in
business in a year because who's paying
$250 to like branch ideas when you could
do that with quorum calm for free like
you could use I don't even know use read
it and up vote things like there's ways
you could kind of work around it for
free but it's it's say anyway so I'm
doing a solution racing and figuring out
how do we how do we bring people
together for a conversation how do we
have a feature it how we actually make
it in the world and there's people with
projects who are out in the world who I
don't think in my thing they're not
doing it right they're not they're not
doing it for their mission right if what
the idea note or Monday comm wanted to
have the most impact then it would be
free or cheap to use but of course they
also need to make money they need to
make make enough money to keep the
lights on looking food on their table
and roof over their heads but they all
the apps seem to price themselves at
that like what they need and how many
people they are so they divided by that
which isn't actually what people are
willing to pay whereas if we
collectively could get 10,000 people
together and everyone put in $10 we have
$100,000 to buy somebody's app now that
sounds like a low price to pay for
somebody's app and it is but somebody
who wants their app to exist in the
world and that we now own it together so
that we don't need to pay for member we
don't need to pay like to truly make
something that is a team building team
organizing app we could create that from
the ground up ourselves with 10,000
hundred thousand dollars no problem it
since it already exists out there we
could also buy one that already exists
and maybe it's more than a hundred
thousand dollars but the more because
we're just starting out of course one
probably gonna have to pay more than we
would normally because people don't know
if that's a sustainable model but the
idea that the collective can buy your
technology from you how much have you
put in now how much money because that's
ridiculous the startups here did the
money come from like if you want it to
still exist in the world then we can buy
it and keep it in the world and at the
same time it might look nothing like
what what you wanted to yet but that we
could do that we could buy one of the
the existing team building ones together
if we were one of the things we aim to
do is figure out what the team building
ones are which ones are owned by because
Google and Facebook but if your other
options to be eventually bought out by
Facebook or Google or you can be bought
out by the human collective people who
like we all own this together and then
we were going to improve it together
it's approaching it from the opposite
way it's like instead I think two of
them I'd still I can't even give them
pricing but they laugh anyway so then
they have the free option then when you
sign up it's not free they're like well
if you qualify and you sit through a
demo you might qualify for only $50 a
month I'm like um I get it any real
legitimate not-for-profit that does
fundraising and has money should be able
to afford $50 a month but not startup
startup nonprofits not like hey I have
an idea that might help in the
coronavirus situation I want to be able
to use this tool to find a team and work
through it that is the level I want I
want it to be Facebook I want it to be
accessible to everybody so that anyone
can join the team and anyone can can use
those tools to break down a task and how
to to follow are the ideas for
generating actually being made into the
world and I don't know which ones all of
them come with free free free trial so
having a free trial for each of them not
by yourself but having a group of five
to ten people working on it working
through any saying here's what we like
about it here's what we don't like about
it here's the pricing structure and
going through all of them like that and
then at the end saying well if we're
going to recreate one from the ground up
what features
if we could buy one of these right now
which one would it be and then we could
possibly approach them and say hey we
live in New Times New Times do you want
this to exist in the world do you want
to be be team building app that is
available to the world for free what do
you need to be able to do that if they
need to in order to for their app just
to run they need to make thirty thousand
dollars a month we need to figure out
how to come up with $30,000 right months
so that we can we can run that and make
it available for everyone but it's only
something that they would voluntarily be
invited to do right that it's not we're
taking over your app and we own it now
once we've done that with enough
industries will have more buying will
have more buying power
it'll be how do we give this person what
they're entitled to instead of can
lowball them or highball them can we pay
them billions of millions of dollars for
something that really is imperfect
millions of dollars that we could
recreate for tens of thousands of
dollars or work because we're a monopoly
in the because we represent the people
and we go to an industry and we're like
listen there's gonna be one menu app at
the end of this no one's gonna use yours
and pay $10 a month when ours is free do
you want to be the free one once we have
five or six under our belts showcase
that then everyone's gonna want to come
to the table and be and be part of it so
that their they don't so that they're
the ones whose employees are still
employed so they're the ones whose ideas
still in the world and and yet this the
difference between efficiency and
redundancy that right now in the world a
lot of our world is designed for maximum
efficiency and yet it's not because it's
designed for profit which is
incentivized to give you maximum
efficiency so monopolies are
incentivized in our world right there's
a reason Amazon's getting more and more
share of the market because they're able
to be more and more efficient and pass
some of that savings on to the consumer
but a lot of it goes to just be Sousa
and shareholders and so you need a
balance between efficiency redundancy
you don't want one factory that builds
everything for the world
you always want at least two I don't
know why this cover you into my
at the same time but I really hate when
I have to have one bathroom when there's
two of us and there's only one bathroom
as soon as there's two bathrooms I can
share that with ten people I don't care
but like I need to know what you're
having to shower I also have access to a
toilet it's like I need to be at least
two bedroom two bath rooms in any place
that even it's like an Airbnb or
something and I think that's a lot of
people feel that way
cuz it's hard to share one bathroom it's
not as hard to share two bathrooms and
it's not saving me somehow it's the same
for if you have one factory and
something happens and or chipping
changes that you don't want a factory at
every factory in every country and every
factory in every municipality that's not
that that does redundancy to the extreme
and we all pay the price for that but
efficiency on the other end is one
factory that provides it for everyone so
that we can provide it for as cheap as
possible and the problem is if
transportation goes down the factory
goes down for whatever reason you don't
have that at all and so you want some
amount of redundancy and you want
efficiency right now we don't really
have either because the efficiency that
does exist goes just like who profits
from that efficiency it's not us it's
the shareholders and it's I do think we
can have the best of both worlds
so those those two things do you have a
trade-off we can have a world where we
look at okay it makes sense for every
country to have their own toilet paper
factory if we're gonna be using toilet
doesn't make sense to talk about that's
a whole other discussion but if we're
going to be using toilet paper it makes
sense for each country to have their own
toilet paper Factory it makes sense even
possibly urban neighborhood to have
their own toilet paper Factory if you
can feed paper into it right if instead
of paper getting collected and ships
over somewhere else and it gets made
into something and then maybe it's made
me toilet I have to pay its premium for
her reusable toilet paper or not reused
to be army recycled toilet paper if it
can literally just be with psycho my
kids know it's become the toilet paper
for our for our um community eventually
like there's
if we're having a massive factory it
doesn't make sense to have one at every
block
if we're having a if the factory is
small enough that it makes sense that
it's made there but having a widget
that's part of a respirator being made
every block doesn't make sense but I
mean 3d printing does and so there's a
way that we when it's tough top-down
strong word when you have a corporation
that's that's making decisions for
profit it's gonna make different
decisions because it's making the
decisions just for profit which means
it's picking efficiency over an unseen
almost every time to the point where
there's no it's fragile the entire
system is fragile because everyone and
we're about to see our economy collapse
because because everyone who's high risk
for the people who are entrepreneurs and
they don't know how to mitigate risk
so they've they've leveraged every sense
of their business and they have tons of
debt coming in and their their income is
enough to pay their debt but they're not
having income coming in granular
bottom-up approach I don't even buy
granular granular bottom-up approach
maybe you can I mean I could play look
up what the definition is but that
generally isn't sufficient because um
you might not have the same definition
as Neuville and I don't have a saint of
ensure that I buy a bottom-up granular
approach I think because the other piece
of this is also diversity right not just
do we want access to toilet paper yes um
do I get access to the brands of toilet
paper that I want it's right I want it
to be soft and durable and whatever the
things for paper are and so if we can
maximize for all the like toilet paper
is one of those things you probably
could maximize for all of that but if
your pasta sauce right someone likes
pasta sauce that has chunky vegetables
in it somebody wants vegetables in it
but they want it pureed somebody wants
you know vegetables to touch it besides
the tomato it's clinical in it and so
something want no garlic right so
there's you need diversity of options
and does it make sense in a tomato back
in to make tomato sauce it doesn't make
sense to make it individually because
that's not efficient right or there's a
reason most of us buy our tomato sauce
and we don't make it from scratch even
though it tastes really good from
scratch if you have the right recipe
having a one big tomato sauce back
tree in Canada that makes different all
the different versions would give us
kind of the best world but like anyway
it's figuring out the math of how many
do we need and from the bottom up the
homes are lost in the sauce yes yes we
definitely and that's for like the
technology and the tools come in is that
you one you don't figure out how much
pasta sauce it's everybody and they're
all lead at how many it's that's where
the solution racing or we are coming up
with the solution for 10,000 people if
there were 10,000 people in Canada who
wanted a brand of pasta sauce that we
wanted to use then we would have one
factory and it would ship out to
everywhere in Canada as we grew we'd say
oh you know what each factory is this
big and it can it can make ten thousand
or surpass today how about like that you
figure out the map for when does it make
sense of a second one where does it make
sense to put that second line and then
it can you can grow from there because
if you if you're in Australia you want
it doesn't make sense to ship it from
here but you actually since it's not for
profit since it's owned by all of us not
just Canadians it's open source so we'll
tell you how to start a tomato factory
in Australia you have 10,000 people you
need to have 10,000 people first find
her ten thousand people who like pasta
sauce and so creating the databases and
the ability to share that information
and be able to create a system together
is what I'm trying to figure out how to
do in the world is how not because
anything can be solved basically what
10,000 people and $100,000 or sorry to
solve this wrong word anything can be
made extremely better by having 10,000
people $100,000 working on it because it
also I don't need you to agree on what
my ten thousand people are doing if you
don't want to be part of it you can go
start your own 10,000 people right so if
we're trying to figure out pasta sauce
we've somehow found 10,000 people who
like pureed vegetable pasta sauce and
that's all we're concentrating on if
you're someone who likes chunky pasta
sauce you wouldn't come be a part of
that or if we started out a part of that
and we found out 99 percent of people
like pureed and only 1 percent of people
like the other one we're gonna
concentrate on the 90 91 but you know
you're the 1% how do we find you your
ninth
you know people so you also get your
your thing that you want and it might
make sense if I think I'll probably be
more off this away like 1% of people at
what Puri passes laws that has all the
vegetables in it but having um the one
that is the 1% that only people want
yeah that one being I'm okay if that one
goes down we can have one factory making
that in the world and it shipped so and
they give the ship the shipping itself
has to be put into the math as well
right there's a real true cost to that
in energy and time and we can only make
that so efficient even with extremely
renewable energy there's still a time
like involved there's still that like
the nutrients are slightly last by it by
it moving especially with actual produce
and so having the math there and having
it be modular granular equals modular I
don't know I can't read that one better
the other one first yes yes yeah yeah
modular so that like but I definitely
having a franchise system or instead of
you want to McDonald's and you happen to
be exactly like McDonald's it's more of
an open source model right we're like
hey you want to start a burger
restaurant these places started to
burger restaurant and here's how you do
it with with the employees being paid
well here's how you like here's the
different iterations and when we have
that process it's very hard to compete
with that in the outside world in what I
call what what I call gave me I invented
that what we call game a like the
current I didn't know did not create
that but like what I would call
capitalism which some people think is
not the definition it's like everything
up to this point is giving hey Nick good
vibes to you to Nick he just wants to be
getting part of this I had quite the fun
exchange this morning with somebody on
gave me it was it was he said I don't
have agency because I'm not a man this
is basically what he said for real
these days but so we started out this
this my class thanks for stopping by
your work is much appreciated but I
don't know us or was that agency
granular modular that having option
for every city that aren't going to be
the same in every one is it not going to
be the same solution that 10,000 people
come up with but why bring create it
when 10,000 people already came up with
one right if it works in any way you
just need to tweak something than tweak
it if you do need to truly come from the
bottom up and recreate a whole new one
then tell us your process and why and
the more we're willing to work together
in that where I don't need I don't need
you to agree on what pasta sauce is the
best we can all have our pasta sauce I
don't need you to agree on what what
metrics are nestlings us tangential
tension let me just look up antenna
gentle I'm thinking about it any
mathematical terms which I don't think
I'll be able to extrapolate what that is
related to along a tangent verging from
a previous course of line erratic hardly
touching peripheral would be tension so
like that is what I'm proposing it is
something alongside our existing
capitalism that is very profit driven
and uber competitive having the polar
opposite of that doesn't mean you have
to pull yourself out of this one and put
yourself into this one and this was all
pretty Cova 19 where our capitalism was
looking like it was gonna chug on for
another couple years were much closer to
collapse right now and so needing this
to exist in the world where you have a
space to be cooperative where you're
giving as much as you want to give and
it's not about reciprocity but if
everyone wants reciprocity like if you
don't if you're not willing to give
unless everyone else is giving as well
those are the conversations we need to
have and we'll need to build that into
the system but if right now what's
happening with kovat 19 people are
giving no one's knocking on their
neighbor's door asking if they've given
enough it's you make cookies for a
neighbor did you go grocery shopping for
senior citizens then I'm not going to
people who are just giving what they
want to give because it feels good they
don't have time they have time on their
hands they have the ability they want to
help they want to feel like they're
contributing and so if we can tap into
that and give them another another
option I have one stream yard yeah wanna
come join Nick I'm only on for another
19 minutes so I have a conversation with
Jordan in 45 minutes but the idea is I'm
doing this every day
any
to 9:30 in my time so that's I'm down
for 42 minutes so 42 minutes ago is when
I go live and I would love other people
to join me at this time
it's so much easier having a
conversation with someone and
interacting with the comments rather
than doing this by myself which I'm not
the best at the talking to the camera
god better I've had practice but yes
close to building upon onedrive already
exists
building a Pomodoro exists and not just
and the issue is though like yeah we can
build on what already exists but it's so
broken that capitalism is or game a
whatever you want to call it is I
attribute it's like the the house and
the Weasleys it's held up by magic like
it's someone you can think back to her
our time as hunter-gatherers where our
life was much more simple and then as we
grew bigger we need more complexity we
needed kind of a central leader and key
this our economic system that has come
up is basically the reason I say it's
Lisa's house is that instead of central
planning which is communism which has
its own home box who really kind of suck
at central planning as a species
capitalism game a has been there ad hoc
solutions so it's like I have a vision
of something I want to create in the
world I want to maximize my profit so
I'm gonna lie I'm gonna or just be
blinders to the truth so that I can
maximize that right so that everything
we do within that system creates
externalities good and bad and then it's
up to the next person to solve the its
value so my vision of the world like my
idea for a business creates new problems
that somebody else solves and then we
have this very extremely complex system
that like when one piece Falls the whole
thing Falls and because it's like oh god
if they don't have insurance then we all
this stuff is based on having insurance
so the insurance went out because of
yeah maybe you want to join me tomorrow
but I won't give you the link I will
send you the link in in a Facebook
I'm gonna want to stay up longer and I
can't fifty minutes all right I sent you
the link on Facebook and so at the ad
hoc solutions and so it's not about
necessarily like dismantle e in that
house it's about figuring out what is
keeping it up because it's not magic and
then what like right now with Cove in
nineteen what we need to be figuring out
what our governments are doing whatever
job they can do it figuring out how to
mitigate that that stress increases the
tools the masks and the the respirators
and everything else is like we need to
be figuring out how we're going to feed
ourselves in six months to a year and
there's very little we can do on an
individual basis I can grow a garden out
my yard but if people are hungry they're
gonna come eat it there's I don't
actually gonna have access to labor in
if everybody in Vancouver is guerilla
gardening on the on the city boulevards
and we're planting enough food that it
doesn't matter if people come and take
it we're good but we need that now we
need that to be how many now and welcome
Nick yeah it's okay if we only have 15
minutes left or less I mean maybe I like
it but Nick we rejoin go out and come
back in because it's extremely laggy I
can't do anything on my end I except I
could leave and come back in but can you
like leave completely cuz I don't think
that's gonna work maybe it does though
just dropping you down and back up I
don't think we're redoing cuz it's like
turn it off and back on
here we go all right hoping that works
sorry learning by doing are you doing in
in these very interesting times yeah
unfortunately I don't have much time
left for things that are not work or
family because we have to take care of
our son well I mean luckily we both work
part time and do home office and can do
home office but we also have to take
care of Felix and so there's not much
time left for things also you know like
like it's hard to say that I think the
the prolonged time together has revealed
some issues that it's actually good if
we kind of just focus on them or at
least so we have done for the last week
and only yesterday I started like
thinking again okay how could I do
something you know like towards the
general public how can I participate and
do something useful
but yes like naturally by living your
life you seem to be contributed in a
pretty profound way like just and this
is why I was talking about you where I
think listening it was like but I don't
give myself enough credit I'm like
there's more I need to be doing in fact
I had a bit of a breakdown last week
because I was like there needs I'm
there's something I should be doing in
this Cove in 19 thing cuz this is my
normal staying at home I don't need to
readjust this is my normal but putting
the weight of the world on my shoulders
is also my normal that I have to kind of
get over and be like you're but showing
up in my own way I'm doing the idea
cafes I'm doing the solution raising of
having live conversations and you also
show up very strongly just by living
your life right with the polls that you
give and the conversations you have I
think that any amount
and racing your kid is important very
good and what you said like so many I
don't know if you saw are you friends
Akira on bass no have you seen her live
her live videos with her husband but
they're working through their their
issues they're amazing I recently yeah
the last week or so they've done two or
three earned her present they also have
a youtube channel called laptop therapy
or something like that but they're doing
someone on Facebook and it's it's just
interesting so like yeah a lot of
marriages ever I don't know anyone it
can be locked up with their family and
not opens up right like there's a
certain even if you normally go for a
walk to cool off you're like okay I
can't do that five or six times today
like it brings up every it brings up
everything else
I mean I'm realizing more and more to
what degree these energy or bias towards
action which you know this manic energy
is actually a way to hide or avoid
certain feelings of sadness or difficult
feelings in general you know like this
and it's weird because it feels good
right but it doesn't mean that you're
effective right it's like need to do
something that these days and yeah I
mean if I was completely in that state a
couple of weeks ago and I had to slow
down and just take a step back and I
think many I I don't know you might have
a similar kind of character that is
always like oriented towards building
like in a constructive mode you know
like and I certainly have that and you
know this is what I've been learning
like this year did that is manic energy
has its downside and sometimes the right
thing is not to do but I suffer it's
painful no and it's hard it's hard to do
nothing and it's hard to like I my
nervous system shuts down when it's
under stress and all I can do is sleep
and I think the world would experience
that in that right now we're like we're
going through this
collective trauma that's like people
there's nothing to do right like you you
can this isn't a war and yet it is like
the enemy is invisible and most of us
have very little we can do about it
right like I'm not gonna come up with
the vaccine I'm not gonna come up with
how to fold the protein even with my
biology background but I maybe can come
up with a system to help nurses if their
house is clean right like there's other
things that could be being done that is
to support those people who are on the
frontline and then dealing with the
things that are happening six months to
a year down the road the people don't
even want to deal with because there's
food in the supermarket I'm like but is
there food at the supermarket in six
months to a year like this is what we
need to be dealing with is making sure
that whatever is truly important in our
society is still being made because
we've made it right we haven't left it
up to the other as you can see they're
like to me this is an amazing crisis
because it's both like a baby apocalypse
where it's actually fairly benign yeah
not it's like the virus itself only
kills 1% of people and we're reacting
I'm really impressed that we're all stay
home during this that it's not how I
thought society would react to this I
thought we'd be like 1% who cares the
economy has got to keep chugging on I am
astounded that this is happening and yet
at the same time that brings up a lot of
like okay
now the world's ready and we gotta go
and it's manic energy and many
technology absolutely comes in a cost
and it's like okay this timeline didn't
change it's like we need to we do need
to wrap it make everything more rapid
and yet at the same time if you're in
that energy you actually can't do
anything so it is it's like okay taking
the time to call making sure I'm like if
ever I needed to meditate daily no it is
the time I've always had the time
something home and now my kids home but
like to deal with that to deal with all
of it like collective meditation episode
on your own tell is I think one of the
best things we can be doing right now
and I feel like I do need to take action
and so this is this is what I'm doing I
was doing it at a much different time
but my brain turns off by the evening of
his unit at 6:00 p.m. but this is now
the time that I'm gonna be doing it's
only day two you know it says day four
because I did - at 6 p.m. and
now I'm doing minute 30 yeah I mean I
that's the thing right I have enjoyed
most of your things because I have a
limited time window where I can be
active and it's not this so this is
purely by chance that you know I'm
available and recently it hasn't been
even that you know like we have we were
just going to sleep and waking up and
doing everything that needs to be done
back to sleep laughs but it was like I
guess therapeutic you know like what
walking with my child and resisting the
temptation to do you know listen to
something forecast etcetera those have
been the most therapeutic moments this
year you know just walking and it's
happened a couple of times it just you
know just had to start crying because
things were coming up and but yeah the
this manic energy I think it's fun it's
interesting how its associated with
meaning right like it you in a sense
it's almost too much meaning and like
more meaning than that then one can
handle in a way and but I was sorry I
have many kind of trains of thoughts at
the moment I wanted to ask you like see
you're great to talk to
Durga Hall yeah I reached I've been
meeting to reach out to him for a while
but I always assume that he's super busy
and he is super busy but I was he was
like a link for you on Thursday and so
we made a disappointment on Monday
because I talked to him only one other
time and that was when I first remember
it's that conversation it's the only
time I can actual conversation with him
and so much has changed in six months
that I just want maybe you feel okay now
is the time to do each other part of
he's like what are we talking about I
don't know like it's not like I need his
specific opinion on something I just
kind of want to tell him what I've been
up to in this space and I want to hear I
know I think he has his own idea that
he's working towards but it's not like
like ready for public consumption but it
was brought to our attention and like
ego making a conversation by someone who
didn't know it wasn't for public
and so I want to kind of talk to him
about that if he's open to it but I just
find out how he's doing in this time
period but they posted something on his
Facebook which was like needing to take
action and that the basis of what I
interpreted eyes it's like the
government's not going to solve this we
involve it and it's always a nobody has
30 I was like hey I am like I feel like
with the solution raising specifically
working in that things in a way that I
think it is powerful like to be able to
bring people together for a conversation
and generate a solution even a solution
raising isn't perfect which of course
it's not how does this move forward so
there are more people on board and then
there's also like another traveler we
are bringing people together for
hopefully so they can bring their
projects and we can create something
that helps all of our projects but that
hasn't been as a Racine age as well and
it's just that like in the gaming space
I have put out a ton of stuff that some
of its pristine flow and some of it
isn't and I can't know which what is and
what isn't and so part of why we're
doing together attacking another project
was that one of the things that got the
most interest was asking people what
their projects right and being a project
for easy and everyone's like yeah I
don't want a project for eighteen but
people don't necessarily want to come
and read other people's projects and
everyone thinks their ideas is the idea
that's gonna save the world but no one
kind of wants to like let go of there's
a straight something else and it's like
okay so how can we work from that space
but then we finally had last Saturday we
had other people join us or it was just
Bentley a drill and I so we're holy I
like that approach you know it's fart
basically right like it's this instead
of resisting that things aren't the way
you expect them you would like them to
be you kind of like proceed from there
you see okay this is the situation what
what's the affordance here to use a
monitor always idea right that the world
is screaming with affordances but yeah
you need to kind of like be in in a
sense very not ruthless but yeah accept
reality as it is right like okay this is
and yeah like put yourself out there
which is which is great you know this is
just doing things and seeing what works
see what was the like talking to no one
and then maybe someone shows up I've
only I've done it was started at 6:00
p.m. and then I realized that does not
work for me but my brother was on for
the first one it was much better than
the second one I was on by myself it was
like I don't like those sorry what time
is it right now it is nice or nice so
right now is when I would usually so I
caught in an hour earlier and I'm doing
I'm going to be doing it I mean seven
days a week possibly um so any time that
any time you're available during this
time period I realize it's a small file
it's much like okay she's on my pad
she's good I would recommend something
because I've been doing something
similar right
my live streams I do them now like
because I I paid for for the paid
version of so I stream on on YouTube and
Facebook and I post the link to the to
the actual session in the description so
that people just you know you can always
send them up hi there someone is
watching just look in the description
click on it and then you can still you
know decide whether to yeah you know
actually the description of the YouTube
video yeah or the or the Facebook post
because stream you are just makes a post
for you are also not you're also a man
in case you didn't know I feel like
weirdos show up more frequently for
women's like on periscope even when
people like join them they just are
weird but I can try and I was gonna ask
you if you've had where people join
actually that's not gonna be a very good
accurate depiction of my experience
because I remember they're actually the
first time I did is to to gamers joins
to drunk gamers who want from your
gaming I don't know where they found my
livestream smell which is fine and also
stream art works pretty well because you
can see it right so if they're naked or
something could be like
yeah add them or not to the conversation
which is different from like zoom for
example if you have like this public
zooming put people who just just sore me
and but no I like you actually have
control that's why I and I really like
this tool a lot and I only know it
thanks to yourself I think it's funny no
one's followed my affiliate link so I
get any kind of money but I think
there's no sorry no no it's all it's
like 10 to 12 people probably because I
again don't pay for it so now I'm under
my brothers anyway I'm like cuz we're
abusing Jack and he's using it for a
wiki lecture and then I'm like yeah why
not now I don't have to like ration my
20 hours just go on yeah and no I like
that idea I don't go logging on Facebook
I think because I don't I don't know why
I don't go live on face but partly
because of my solution raising I'm more
calm you are life on Facebook right now
like you know I'm not I'm live on
periscope and on YouTube I saw yeah yeah
yeah because because it's like Twitter
is my number one social media for not
that's not Facebook related and then
Facebook it's like my friends and family
and game be people who I like I wouldn't
post this in Gabey just like what it
counted shoot the for an hour every
morning and that's a lot but it's just
like he's showing up saying how can we
move towards half getting 10,000 people
and be showing how who shows up how does
it go
let's see how it works yeah I created
the Facebook group and I deleted my
facebook account last year and I only
recreated it to join the Facebook group
so I only have friends from the game
with yeah I mean sorry if you have to
leave that please
but like periscope is on my Twitter as
well so I can actually just comment on
it and post the link there as well it's
not likely to have some weirdos
violence or you know like half the time
I'm stoned night of 8:30 in the morning
so this is also 6 p.m. didn't work so
well during a juryman stress because it
turns out I can't make it to 6 p.m.
without these days which is fine I'm
Onan and I'm figuring it out but that's
ok 30 works better and so anyway but
posting the link underneath periscope as
well as on the Twitter post periscope
automatically generates and in the
description I don't know about the
periscope because I don't use it so but
yeah that's what I do right like just
because for now on YouTube I was you
know like I wanted to join I would have
gone directly if I had seen the link
into this place absolutely I will do
that and see how it goes I mean that's
also part of us right is just doing what
feels safe enough and allowing it to
happen I'm like that's what I could do
is I could my he goes on the back burner
all the time like I'm good with just
showing up which a lot of people aren't
ok do it in fact it makes other people
uncomfortable like this is how we create
about the world is like figure out what
works and work through your own
yeah to do that in public the more other
people can get benefits that's not
that's the curse of knowledge for me I
tend to forget that it's not natural for
most people to just you know show up and
the clumsiness it's treatable I mean I I
worked on it and now I'm comfortable
enough that I was like because of my
social anxiety and I've worked through
it and gotten here I'm like what do you
mean you all don't have social anxiety
just come be on camera but everyone has
virtually anxiety and it's stressful
being live on camera when it could be
there forever
I'm like there's two viewers this is a
safe enough like come be part of it
in a few weeks maybe when those hundreds
of viewers if we can make it that far
then like I understand people getting
look horn or shine but there was a time
I went live on YouTube after being used
to going live on periscope and someone
came in or what I was like I know
I'm talking to yourself who is zero is
so and then one person comes on you're
like well this is awkward I don't I
don't want to talk like my beard okay
I'm gonna go in ten minutes before your
time something before talking to Jordans
or anything I will say hi all right
I can't everybody else peterborough
anytime you want to come on I will be
posting like I said the link below on
butter or not and you're always welcome
back alright this a big like yes and
broadcast first